basemark.com 2019-05-22

# Privacy Policy - Basemark Corporate

### Objective and scope of privacy policy

Basemark Oy is a software development & consultancy company established as a Limited Company in Finland and having a US Limited company, Basemark Ltd. Incorporated in Deleware, USA (“Basemark” or “we” in this document).

Your privacy is important to Basemark. We also want to be transparent so that you know what information is gathered when you visit our websites  ([www.basemark.com](https://www.basemark.com/)), (https://web.basemark.com/) and (<https://powerboard.basemark.com/>) or when you otherwise use our services or interact with us.

### Personal information

For this Privacy Policy, “Personal Information” means any information provided to or collected by Basemark, recorded in any form, about an identifiable individual, or an individual whose identity may be inferred or determined from the information. This Privacy Policy does not cover any information, recorded in any form, about more than one individual where the identity of the individuals is not known and cannot be inferred from the information, (“Aggregated Information” in this document). Basemark retains the right to use Aggregated Information in any way that it reasonably determines is appropriate.

One of Basemark’s core activities is benchmarking hardware & software. Only a minimum amount of information is collected from individual users for benchmarking purposes. This minimal amount of information has been selected to minimize the amount of personal information collected during the benchmarking process and is typically limited to IP address, device model information and time stamps. Once individual performance data is collected it is anonymized and combined with a plurality of other anonymized performance data which forms aggregated information.

### Our websites and cookies

Basemark may use cookies, web beacons/pixel tags, log files and other technologies to collect certain information about visitors to our websites, and recipients of our newsletters, invitations and other communications. In general, if you are simply using the Basemark.com website information collection is limited to cookie and analytic information.

Our websites may contain links to other websites, and content from other websites such as Facebook, Twitter, and Linkedin. The use of such content is subject to said website’s own privacy policy instead of ours.

###  Types of information collected by Basemark

As a general rule, all information concerning the business and affairs of a person or organization acquired: (1) for the purpose of determining whether Basemark will enter into a business relationship; or (2) in the course of a business relationship, shall be held in strict confidence and not revealed to anyone unless expressly or implicitly authorized by the person or organization concerned or permitted or required by applicable law. A business relationship develops when a person or company agree to purchase a service from Basemark, to license a product from Basemark, or to use a product from Basemark.

In the course of its relationship with you, Basemark may need to collect, use, and sometimes, disclose various types of Personal Information for various purposes associated with the scope of the services we provide as directed by you or your organization. Given the nature of Basemark products & services, it is impractical to list all of types of Personal Information that may be collected, used or disclosed. However, the Personal Information we collect may include:

  * your full name;
  * contact information, such as your address, telephone number, e-mail address, or job titles;
  * whether you have subscribed or unsubscribed from any of our mailing lists, or accepted any of our invitations;
  * your payment information;
  * any other Personal Information that you voluntarily choose to provide to us;
  * as we use analytic services from Google, any information gathered by these services including your usage data regarding your visit on one or more of our sites. Basemark may use this analytic information for developing and marketing our products and services. You may disable the Google analytics services by [CLICKING HERE](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). Please note that this opt out is specific for each browser and device.
  * your usage of one or more of our websites through “cookies” which enable us to make certain parts of the site easier to use. Cookies are small text files on your computer’s hard drive, allowing your computer to be recognized by our website. You may refuse to accept cookies and delete existing cookies using the settings on your Internet browser. If your Internet browser settings prevent the use of cookies, you may be unable to access or use fully certain parts of our website. When you enter our website, we may also collect information about your computer, IP address, operating system and browser type, for example, for statistical purposes or purposes of system administration. This information generally comprises data that does not allow individual identification of information related to a specific user.

### Use and discloser personal information

Basemark uses and discloses personal information for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. Basemark does not sell, trade, barter or exchange for consideration any Personal Information it has obtained to third parties.

Additionally, Basemark stores your data in locked facilities behind firewalls. Information collected through analytics services may be stored outside the European Economic Area if the analytics services provider is located outside the European Economic Area. In these cases we take steps to ensure that your personal information is processed lawfully, secured and monitored for data breaches.

Except for the above, we do not regularly transfer your data outside the EEA and we aim to keep cloud based services within the EEA as much as possible.

Basemark may use and disclose Personal Information for the following purposes:

  * Establishing your identity and compliance with “Know Your Client” regulations and other legal obligations: which may require you to provide name, address, employment/business information, and/or other legally mandated forms of identification;
  * Billing: which will include the collection of names, addresses, banking and/or financial details;
  * Provision and development of Services/Products: which will include any Personal Information necessary to provide services requested by you or your organization;
  * Analytics: we may also use and analyze the Personal Information provided to us to offer you additional services or products, as well as to track and manage your consent preferences, event reservations and any unsubscribe requests. You may, at any time, advise Basemark that you would not like to receive any further information;
  * Internal record keeping;
  * Answering your queries, and/or providing you with information or materials you have asked to receive;
  * Market research;
  * Marketing our own products and services to you by email or other means if you have opted to subscribe to one our mailing lists;
  * To keep your information and preferences accurate. For example, from time to time, we may ask you (by email or otherwise) to review your contact details and mailing list preferences and update them as necessary;
  * Any purpose which is permitted or required by applicable law; and
  * To carry out any other purpose which is disclosed to you and to which you consent.

If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive marketing emails or news letters from Basemark, please follow the unsubscribe link in any of our messages or send an email to unsubscribe@basemark.com with your request.

Personal Information may be stored outside of the jurisdiction in which you live, if a third party provider or other entity to whom we disclose personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy is located outside of that jurisdiction. In such cases, Personal Information may be subject to the local laws of the jurisdictions within which it is collected, used, disclosed and/or stored, and may be accessed by governmental authorities in those jurisdictions.

Personal Information may also be subject to transfer to another organization in the event of corporate transaction such as a merger or change of ownership. This will occur only if the parties have entered into an agreement under which the collection, use and disclosure of the information is restricted to those purposes that relate to the business transaction, including a determination whether or not to proceed with the business transaction, and is used by the parties to carry out and complete the business transaction.

Lastly, we may disclose your Personal Information for any other purpose to which you consent.

### Limiting collection, use, disclosure and retention of personal information

Basemark may collect your Personal Information in one or more forms but will only do so by lawful means and only for necessary purposes that have been disclosed to you.

Personal Information collected in any form will only be retained by Basemark so long as it is required: a) for the purpose for which it was collected; b) to be retained by law; or c) to address any issues that may arise at a later date. When your Personal Information is no longer required for these identified purposes, Basemark uses secure procedures to destroy, delete, erase or convert the Personal Information into an anonymous form.

### Consent

Your provision of Personal Information to Basemark confers that you agree and consent that we may collect, use and disclose your Personal Information under this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with these terms, you are requested not to provide any Personal Information to us. Certain services can only be offered if you provide Personal Information to us, but other information may be optional. If you choose not provide us with any required Personal Information, we may not be able to offer you certain services.

Consent may be given in different ways such as: a) expressly by signing a document, agreeing through electronic means or verbally; or b) implicitly by providing the Personal Information voluntarily.

Please note that there are circumstances where the use and/or disclosure of Personal Information may be justified or permitted or where Basemark may or must disclose information without consent, in accordance with the applicable law.

Where obliged or permitted to disclose information without consent, Basemark will not disclose more information than is required for the purpose that obligates or permits us to disclose such information.

You have the right to revoke your consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information at any time. However, revocation of your consent may result in our inability to provide services or products to you. We will discuss with you the reason we need your Personal Information and why the revocation of your consent affects our ability to provide the service or product to you.

### Storage and security

Basemark will protect personal information by reasonable security safeguards against loss or theft, as well as unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use or modification.

### Accuracy and access

Basemark endeavors to ensure that any Personal Information provided and in its possession is as accurate, current and complete as necessary for the purposes for which we use that information.

You have a right to request access to your Personal Information and to request a correction to it if you believe it is inaccurate. In the event that you believe that your Personal Information is not accurate or you wish access to your Personal Information, you may make a request to contact person below.

We will always endeavor to provide timely access to your Personal Information. However, we may verify your identity to our satisfaction prior to doing so. Further, there may be circumstances where access cannot be granted. For example, where access would lead to the disclosure of Personal Information of another individual and that individual refuses to provide consent to the disclosure, or information subject to privilege or other legal restrictions. In such cases you will be notified of the reason why it is not possible to grant access to your Personal Information.

### Amendment of our practices and this privacy policy

This Privacy Policy has been updated on, and is in effect as of **April 11, 2018**. Basemark will from time to time review and revise its privacy practices and this Privacy Policy. In the event of any amendment, an appropriate notice will be posted on Basemark’s websites.

Your continued access to and/or use of our websites or provision of personal information to us after any such changes constitutes your acceptance of, and agreement to this Privacy Policy, as revised. Please periodically review this Privacy Policy so that you know what personal information we collect, how we use it, and with whom we may share it.

### Contact us

If you ever have any questions, complaints or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, any Personal Information you have submitted to Basemark, or if you would like to:

  * access Personal Information that you have already provided so that you can correct or update it, or request that it be deleted, or
  * report any violation of this Privacy Policy

you may contact any Basemark employee with whom you have a relationship or our privacy helpdesk below:

Privacy helpdesk for Basemark Oy

or by mail to

Basemark Oy  
Attn: Privacy  
Albertinkatu 25 B  
00180 Helsinki  
Finland
